<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Silicon Valley Real Estate Video Blog</title>
    <description>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers from PRG Real Estate</description>
    <link>http://prg-re.blog/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://prg-re.blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 13:10:27 -0500</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2017 13:10:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Skip the Home Inspection</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TfdoM8en3J8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you need to have a home inspection?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my opinion, the answer is definitely yes. I even recommend that sellers order an inspection of their home before it hits the market. That way, you can address any issues up front and potential buyers know exactly what they’re getting into.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not all sellers will do this, however, so &lt;strong&gt;homebuyers should definitely order an inspection if one is not provided to them.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t want to end up with any surprises after you’ve closed escrow and moved into the property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why are inspections so important?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homes get worn down after years of wear and tear or deferred maintenance. You may not notice some of these issues just by looking at the home. There may be problems with the crawlspace, the foundation, or the roof. Just because a home looks perfectly staged and freshly painted doesn’t mean that there aren’t any problems hiding behind the walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You don’t want to move in and be surprised by a major plumbing issue.%20http://prg-re.blog/dont-skip-the-home-inspection.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You don’t want to move in and be surprised by a major plumbing issue.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t want to move in and suddenly have to deal with a major plumbing leak or a crack in the foundation. Those kinds of issues can cause significant damage and be very expensive to repair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recommend that every homebuyer orders these three inspections:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The general property inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; The inspector will check all of the mechanics of the home, including plumbing and the electrical system, and let you know if there are any red flags.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The pest and/or termite inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; The inspector will look for any existing, active infestations, as well as conditions that could lead to future infestations. The inspector will then tell you how to resolve or prevent those infestations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. The roof inspection.&lt;/strong&gt; The roof is a big ticket item, so it’s important that you get an assessment of how much longer the roof will last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the findings of those inspections, you can then determine whether you want to negotiate repairs with the seller or walk away from the deal. Make sure that you are comfortable with the amount of work or maintenance that needs to be done on the home before you purchase it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about home inspections or would like to learn more about buying a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/dont-skip-the-home-inspection.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prg-re.blog/dont-skip-the-home-inspection.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Effectively Sell and Buy at the Same Time</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/kXEpk7yTE5k&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can you effectively sell your home and buy a new home at the same time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is a big concern in our market right now, as the market continues to be very competitive. Buying a home can be a challenge, so many people are scared that they won’t be able to find their next home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, I have four tips to help you avoid stress, prevent letdowns, and make the process smoother:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Identify the area you want to move to&lt;/strong&gt; and narrow down criteria for your next house. After your current home is under contract, you don’t want to spend time trying pin down where you want to live next. Do your homework up front and know where you are headed next before listing your current home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Negotiate a rent-back on your current home.&lt;/strong&gt; Sellers can negotiate a rent-back from the buyer and stay in their current property for 30, 60, or even 90 days while they purchase their next home. We’ve even been able to negotiate a rent-back at no cost to the seller because their property is in such high demand. As a seller, the rent-back allows you to move at a smoother pace and find your next home. &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You don’t want to fall in love with a home that you don’t have the ability to purchase.%20http://prg-re.blog/how-to-effectively-sell-and-buy-at-the-same-time.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You don’t want to fall in love with a home that you don’t have the ability to purchase.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Do not submit offers too soon.&lt;/strong&gt; I’ve seen people get let down so much in this market. Some sellers make the mistake of trying to find their replacement property the minute their home hits the market or before they even get an offer. You don’t want to fall in love with a home that you don’t have the ability to purchase. You need to know when the time is right to start actively submitting offers on a new home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Submit a really strong offer.&lt;/strong&gt; Once your current home is under contract—and basically already sold—you can go out, find a home, and submit a really strong offer. Right now, we have a seller who got their home under contract and is ready to close escrow on their new property next week. The seller accepted an all-cash offer on their home, which allowed them to become a cash buyer. So, even with some contingencies in the contract, their offer stood out because they were able to buy the replacement property with cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have a strategy and an experienced agent to guide you, then you can buy and sell a home at the same time—even in this hot market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/how-to-effectively-sell-and-buy-at-the-same-time.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prg-re.blog/how-to-effectively-sell-and-buy-at-the-same-time.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Don’t Homes Sell in Silicon Valley?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wZnBb3EjbQ0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone’s always talking about how hot our market is, but what about the homes that don’t sell for one reason or another? In Santa Clara County in 2016, almost 1,000 homes became expired listings. &lt;strong&gt;Here are the most common reasons a home doesn’t sell in our market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first is the home simply doesn’t show well. If a home is dark, dingy, or cluttered, buyers who walk into it won’t get a chance to visualize themselves in it. This will turn them off and cause them to walk away. If your home doesn’t show well, you will lose buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Don’t let your home become an expired listing statistic.%20http://prg-re.blog/why-dont-homes-sell-in-silicon-valley.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Don’t let your home become an expired listing statistic.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second reason a home might not sell is buyers can’t get into it. If you put too many restrictions on when your home can be shown, fewer people will be able to walk through it and put an offer on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third reason a home might not sell is because the photos might be bad. A home might look amazing in person, but if the photos of it are not professionally done, it will attract fewer people. Remember, almost everyone starts their home search online, and the photos are the first thing they see. If your home’s photos don’t show well, buyers might skip over it and move on to the next home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fourth reason is the home can’t get financing. Most buyers need a mortgage to buy a home, so your home needs to be financeable. If there is a lot of damage to it or there are issues regarding its title, the lender may not want to lend money on your property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final reason is the price is too high. If you’re too ambitious and overprice your property, you won’t have any buyers walking through your door. People are attracted to prices that look good. Your goal should be to create a bidding war—not price people out of contention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your home must be presented well, marketed well, and priced correctly to take advantage of this market.&lt;/strong&gt; You don’t want to end up as an expired listing statistic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about this topic or you’re looking to buy or sell a home in our market, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/why-dont-homes-sell-in-silicon-valley.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prg-re.blog/why-dont-homes-sell-in-silicon-valley.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Steps to Winning a Multiple Offer Situation</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/JwKK7QFk3uY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As everyone knows, the real estate market is red hot right now—especially for sellers. If you’re a buyer, this means you might have to compete against other offers once you find a home you like. &lt;strong&gt;Here are a few tips you can use to make your offer stronger in this situation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, submit a large earnest money deposit. This is the initial deposit you’ll give to the seller once your offer gets accepted. You typically want to deposit at least 3% down. This will show the seller that you’re serious and you have the money to back up your offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Presenting a strong offer right out of the gate will give you the best chance to win.%20http://prg-re.blog/5-steps-to-winning-a-multiple-offer-situation.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Presenting a strong offer right out of the gate will give you the best chance to win.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, &lt;strong&gt;show the seller you’re qualified to buy.&lt;/strong&gt; You’ll want to have a pre-approval letter, but you can take it a step further by getting a full loan commitment letter, which verifies that your loan has already been underwritten and approved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Third, give the seller time to move. Many sellers in our market are selling their property with the intention of moving into a new home, so they may be caught without a place to live once their property sells. If you wrote your offer and said that you would be willing to rent the property back for however long they need to find a new home, that will put you a step ahead of the other buyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fourth, shorten or waive some of your contingency periods if you can. Having the least amount of contingency periods or shortening them will make you look stronger if you can pull that off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;strong&gt;write your best offer.&lt;/strong&gt; A common strategy for sellers is to list the property lower than what they think it will sell for. That means the difference between the list price and the final sale price can be anywhere from 5% to 10%. When writing your offer, you don’t want to count on getting a counteroffer. Presenting a strong offer right out of the gate will give you a much better chance of getting your offer selected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many other details that come into play during a home sale, so if you have any questions or are planning on buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 May 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/5-steps-to-winning-a-multiple-offer-situation.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prg-re.blog/5-steps-to-winning-a-multiple-offer-situation.html</guid>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our Silicon Valley Market Is on Fire This 2nd Quarter</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/j4qYUAIZbTo&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Silicon Valley market is on fire in the second quarter, especially if you’re a seller. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that inventory has risen from 600 homes for sale back in December to roughly 1,200 at the current moment, it’s still near an all-time low. There’s a little bit more to choose from, &lt;strong&gt;but we have just one month of available inventory right now. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our average sale price is $1,000,050, and homes are sitting on the market an average of 20 days before they go under contract. In some areas, it’s a lot quicker than that. Interest rates are in the low 4% range, which is another all-time low. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Our market is on fire, especially if you’re a seller.%20http://prg-re.blog/our-silicon-valley-market-is-on-fire-this-2nd-quarter.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Our market is on fire, especially if you’re a seller.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do these numbers mean?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a seller, it’s still a great time to enter the market.&lt;/strong&gt; If you price your home correctly, present it correctly, and market it properly, you can expect multiple offers, which can drive up your final sale price. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re a buyer, you’re going to have your work cut out for you.&lt;/strong&gt; I recently spoke to a fellow agent who received 19 offers on a listing of hers in San Jose, so it’s going to be tough to get your foot in the door against that level of competition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should be ready to pay significantly more than the asking price for a home and come in strong with your terms. I also encourage you to explore other options than what’s listed on the MLS, Redfin, or Trulia. There are a lot of other sales happening off-market such as ‘For Sale By Owner’ properties and those that are sold between agents. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any other questions about our market or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, feel free to reach out to us. We’d love to help you. 
&lt;br /&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/our-silicon-valley-market-is-on-fire-this-2nd-quarter.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prg-re.blog/our-silicon-valley-market-is-on-fire-this-2nd-quarter.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Determine the Value of Your Silicon Valley Home</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/5CgKjUoyMwQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What’s the best way to determine the value of your house when you’re getting ready to sell? I wanted to let you in on what we do on our team to determine a home’s value before it hits the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we’ll look at data from what has recently sold in the area. We’ll typically look back anywhere from three to six months to find sales to give us the most accurate price. We make sure we compare your home to other homes within 10% to 15% of your square footage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Comparing list prices to their actual sales price tells us how the market is moving in your neighborhood.%20http://prg-re.blog/how-to-determine-the-value-of-your-silicon-valley-home.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Comparing list prices to their actual sales price tells us how the market is moving in your neighborhood.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next, we want to make sure the homes we’re comparing to yours are in similar condition. &lt;/strong&gt;For example, if your home is remodeled, we want to compare it to other homes that are remodeled or updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’ll determine sales trends by comparing list prices and actual sales prices. Are homes selling well above asking price? Maybe they’re selling for less than the asking price. This will also &lt;strong&gt;tell us how fast homes are moving in the area. &lt;/strong&gt;All these factors will help determine where we need to price your home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always recommend you have a professional real estate agent come out to your home for a thorough evaluation if you’re thinking about selling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions or you’d like one of our team members to evaluate your home, give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to help you out!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/how-to-determine-the-value-of-your-silicon-valley-home.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prg-re.blog/how-to-determine-the-value-of-your-silicon-valley-home.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Estate Planning Isn't  Just for the Wealthy</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/UlJFClYSb8w&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estate planning is an important topic for everyone, so today I’m happy to be joined by David Park of estate planning firm Horner Park Law to help me discuss it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estate planning is a complete set of documents that typically includes a will or trust and other things that basically &lt;strong&gt;act as a set of instructions for what you want to happen to your property in the event you pass away or who you want to control it if you’re incapacitated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest misconception about estate planning is that it’s only for the wealthy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=The biggest misconception about estate planning is that it's only for the wealthy.%20http://prg-re.blog/estate-planning-isnt-just-for-the-wealthy.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“The biggest misconception about estate planning is that it’s only for the wealthy.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s true that the wealthy use estate planning to hold onto their wealth, the majority of people use estate planning to avoid probate, which is especially important to homeowners. If you have to go through probate, it takes a long time and costs a lot of money. The probate process usually takes a minimum of one year and can cost tens of thousands of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Probate can be tough because after a loved one passes away, it’s hard to move on when they’re tied up in the probate process in the court system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We really feel strongly that setting up an estate plan is very important, and I’m actually setting up my estate plan with David. I want to share this with you, so we’ll have an estate planning seminar coming up with David and his firm where we’ll go over more details about the process and all the benefits. Stay tuned for more details.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions for David in the meantime, you can reach him at 402-479-2312 or email him at dpark@hornerparklaw.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about buying or selling a home here in the Silicon Valley market, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to seeing you soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/estate-planning-isnt-just-for-the-wealthy.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prg-re.blog/estate-planning-isnt-just-for-the-wealthy.html</guid>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Avoid Damaging Your Credit Score With These Tips</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zxpAi1pOP4o&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re thinking about buying a home or shopping for one right now, having the best credit score possible is in your best interest. &lt;strong&gt;To get you a lower score (which will get you a lower mortgage rate), here are the tips you should follow:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Check for any errors on your credit report.&lt;/strong&gt; You can check it on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.annualcreditreport.com/index.action&quot;&gt;annualcreditreport.com&lt;/a&gt; once a year for free. We see errors all the time on people’s reports. That can bring your credit score down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Pay down your credit card bills as much as possible.&lt;/strong&gt; If you can pay your debts off completely, that’s ideal. However, if you can pay it down by 30% or even 50%, you will be in much better shape&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Never max out your credit cards.&lt;/strong&gt; Doing so will always cause your score to drop&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Wait 12 months to purchase after having credit issues.&lt;/strong&gt; You want to have a clean, solid credit history for at least one year so that your score will start to go up again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Shop for your mortgage interest rates at the same time.&lt;/strong&gt; Ideally, you want to shop around to get the best rate. However, you need to do it in the same 30-day span. You will have to pull your credit for each lender, but if you’re shopping for the same type of mortgage in the same month, it will count as just one inquiry. This will bring your score down, but not by much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Never max out your credit card.%20http://prg-re.blog/avoid-damaging-your-credit-score-with-these-tips.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Never max out your credit card.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this information helps you if you have any questions about buying or selling a home. If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/avoid-damaging-your-credit-score-with-these-tips.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prg-re.blog/avoid-damaging-your-credit-score-with-these-tips.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Ring in the New Year With These 2017 Market Predictions</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gQl1b5rzA9w&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The new year is finally under way, so I wanted to give you my predictions for the 2017 Santa Clara real estate market. I’ll also give you a quick recap of what happened in 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Additionally, I wanted to let you know how thankful we are for your support!&lt;/strong&gt; We hope you had a fantastic New Year and we look forward to working with you this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what did the market at the end of 2016 look like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=Inventory is still incredibly low%20http://prg-re.blog/ring-in-the-new-year-with-these-2017-market-predictions.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“Inventory is still incredibly low”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we saw a little under 15,000 home sales for the year. The average days on market was 37 days, and as of right now there are only about 580 listings, which is very low, and 900 homes pending. The big event was interest rates going up from mid 3% to between 4% and 4.5%, &lt;strong&gt;but those rates are still historically low.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does this mean we can expect to see in 2017?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can definitely expect to see home prices continue to increase, but we will see a decrease in sales. That’s because there is still a shortage of inventory. &lt;strong&gt;Right now we are still in a seller’s market, so buyers need to be strategic about finding a home.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions about what’s going on in our market, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/ring-in-the-new-year-with-these-2017-market-predictions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prg-re.blog/ring-in-the-new-year-with-these-2017-market-predictions.html</guid>
        
        <category>Market Update</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Are Seller Disclosures So Important?</title>
        <description>&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/u4eBw-XwR3U&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently met with a seller who asked me what they should disclose about their home to their buyer. I wanted to answer that question for you today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you were to look up real estate lawsuits, you would see that a good portion of them have to do with seller disclosures, and sellers failing to disclose certain things they know about the property&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt; Whether the roof is a tad leaky in one spot or there is a lot of traffic in the area, you need to disclose it all to the seller. Anything that you know about the property that will affect its marketability is required to be disclosed by law. Here are three tips to help you avoid situations of failing to disclose enough information to the seller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/home/?status=You are required by law to disclose anything you know.%20http://prg-re.blog/why-are-seller-disclosures-so-important.html%20via%40&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; class=&quot;pullquote&quot;&gt;“You are required by law to disclose anything you know.”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Keep up with the maintenance.&lt;/strong&gt; We recommend keeping your systems up to date so that you are in-tune with the condition of your property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Get a home inspection done.&lt;/strong&gt; Having an inspection done before you list is a good idea. The inspector will come, tell you every little thing they find, and provide a nice report. This will also help minimize liability for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Offer a home warranty to the buyer.&lt;/strong&gt; By doing this, you are saying that you’ll cover their main systems if they break down. The buyer will only have to pay a small deductible with a home warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, disclose everything you can think of. You don’t want anything coming back to bite you. If you have any questions for me or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/why-are-seller-disclosures-so-important.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://prg-re.blog/why-are-seller-disclosures-so-important.html</guid>
        
        <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
