<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>PRG Real Estate Podcast</title>
    <link>http://prg-re.blog</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://prg-re.blog"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from PRG Real Estate.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Enrique Medellin</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2017-08-28 13:10:27 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Enrique Medellin</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog/uploads/medellin-podcast-header.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>info@realestatePRG.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Enrique Medellin</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://prg-re.blog/uploads/medellin-podcast-header.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers from PRG Real Estate</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from PRG Real Estate.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>Don’t Skip the Home Inspection</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/dont-skip-the-home-inspection.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-23 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Dont+Skip+the+Home+Inspection.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Do you need to have a home inspection?

In my opinion, the answer is definitely yes. I even recommend that sellers order an inspection of their home before it hits the market. That way, you can address any issues up front and potential buyers know exactly what they’re getting into.

Not all sellers will do this, however, so homebuyers should definitely order an inspection if one is not provided to them. You don’t want to end up with any surprises after you’ve closed escrow and moved into the property.

Why are inspections so important?

Homes get worn down after years of wear and tear or deferred maintenance. You may not notice some of these issues just by looking at the home. There may be problems with the crawlspace, the foundation, or the roof. Just because a home looks perfectly staged and freshly painted doesn’t mean that there aren’t any problems hiding behind the walls.

“You don’t want to move in and be surprised by a major plumbing issue.”

You don’t want to move in and suddenly have to deal with a major plumbing leak or a crack in the foundation. Those kinds of issues can cause significant damage and be very expensive to repair.

I recommend that every homebuyer orders these three inspections:

1. The general property inspection. The inspector will check all of the mechanics of the home, including plumbing and the electrical system, and let you know if there are any red flags.

2. The pest and/or termite inspection. The inspector will look for any existing, active infestations, as well as conditions that could lead to future infestations. The inspector will then tell you how to resolve or prevent those infestations.

3. The roof inspection. The roof is a big ticket item, so it’s important that you get an assessment of how much longer the roof will last.

Based on the findings of those inspections, you can then determine whether you want to negotiate repairs with the seller or walk away from the deal. Make sure that you are comfortable with the amount of work or maintenance that needs to be done on the home before you purchase it.

If you have any other questions about home inspections or would like to learn more about buying a home, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Dont+Skip+the+Home+Inspection.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Dont+Skip+the+Home+Inspection.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Do you really need to order a home inspection? I believe the answer is yes, and there are a few reasons why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Do you really need to order a home inspection? I believe the answer is yes, and there are a few reasons why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Effectively Sell and Buy at the Same Time</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/how-to-effectively-sell-and-buy-at-the-same-time.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-08-01 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+How+to+Handle+2+Real+Estate+Transactions+at+Once.mp4</guid>
        <description>

How can you effectively sell your home and buy a new home at the same time?

That is a big concern in our market right now, as the market continues to be very competitive. Buying a home can be a challenge, so many people are scared that they won’t be able to find their next home.

However, I have four tips to help you avoid stress, prevent letdowns, and make the process smoother:

1. Identify the area you want to move to and narrow down criteria for your next house. After your current home is under contract, you don’t want to spend time trying pin down where you want to live next. Do your homework up front and know where you are headed next before listing your current home.

2. Negotiate a rent-back on your current home. Sellers can negotiate a rent-back from the buyer and stay in their current property for 30, 60, or even 90 days while they purchase their next home. We’ve even been able to negotiate a rent-back at no cost to the seller because their property is in such high demand. As a seller, the rent-back allows you to move at a smoother pace and find your next home. “You don’t want to fall in love with a home that you don’t have the ability to purchase.”

3. Do not submit offers too soon. I’ve seen people get let down so much in this market. Some sellers make the mistake of trying to find their replacement property the minute their home hits the market or before they even get an offer. You don’t want to fall in love with a home that you don’t have the ability to purchase. You need to know when the time is right to start actively submitting offers on a new home.

4. Submit a really strong offer. Once your current home is under contract—and basically already sold—you can go out, find a home, and submit a really strong offer. Right now, we have a seller who got their home under contract and is ready to close escrow on their new property next week. The seller accepted an all-cash offer on their home, which allowed them to become a cash buyer. So, even with some contingencies in the contract, their offer stood out because they were able to buy the replacement property with cash.

If you have a strategy and an experienced agent to guide you, then you can buy and sell a home at the same time—even in this hot market.

If you have any other questions, just give me a call or send me an email. I would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+How+to+Handle+2+Real+Estate+Transactions+at+Once.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+How+to+Handle+2+Real+Estate+Transactions+at+Once.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>How can you buy and sell a home at the same time in our competitive market? I have four tips for you today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>How can you buy and sell a home at the same time in our competitive market? I have four tips for you today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Don’t Homes Sell in Silicon Valley?</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/why-dont-homes-sell-in-silicon-valley.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-06-09 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+Why+homes+don%E2%80%99t+get+sold+in+Silicon+Valley.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Everyone’s always talking about how hot our market is, but what about the homes that don’t sell for one reason or another? In Santa Clara County in 2016, almost 1,000 homes became expired listings. Here are the most common reasons a home doesn’t sell in our market.

The first is the home simply doesn’t show well. If a home is dark, dingy, or cluttered, buyers who walk into it won’t get a chance to visualize themselves in it. This will turn them off and cause them to walk away. If your home doesn’t show well, you will lose buyers.

“Don’t let your home become an expired listing statistic.”

The second reason a home might not sell is buyers can’t get into it. If you put too many restrictions on when your home can be shown, fewer people will be able to walk through it and put an offer on it.

The third reason a home might not sell is because the photos might be bad. A home might look amazing in person, but if the photos of it are not professionally done, it will attract fewer people. Remember, almost everyone starts their home search online, and the photos are the first thing they see. If your home’s photos don’t show well, buyers might skip over it and move on to the next home.

The fourth reason is the home can’t get financing. Most buyers need a mortgage to buy a home, so your home needs to be financeable. If there is a lot of damage to it or there are issues regarding its title, the lender may not want to lend money on your property.

The final reason is the price is too high. If you’re too ambitious and overprice your property, you won’t have any buyers walking through your door. People are attracted to prices that look good. Your goal should be to create a bidding war—not price people out of contention.

Your home must be presented well, marketed well, and priced correctly to take advantage of this market. You don’t want to end up as an expired listing statistic.

If you have any questions about this topic or you’re looking to buy or sell a home in our market, don’t hesitate to give me a call or shoot me an email. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+Why+homes+don%E2%80%99t+get+sold+in+Silicon+Valley.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+Why+homes+don%E2%80%99t+get+sold+in+Silicon+Valley.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If a home doesn’t sell in our market, it’s probably because of a few common reasons.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If a home doesn’t sell in our market, it’s probably because of a few common reasons.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Steps to Winning a Multiple Offer Situation</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/5-steps-to-winning-a-multiple-offer-situation.html</link>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-05-25 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+How+you+can+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As everyone knows, the real estate market is red hot right now—especially for sellers. If you’re a buyer, this means you might have to compete against other offers once you find a home you like. Here are a few tips you can use to make your offer stronger in this situation.

First, submit a large earnest money deposit. This is the initial deposit you’ll give to the seller once your offer gets accepted. You typically want to deposit at least 3% down. This will show the seller that you’re serious and you have the money to back up your offer.

“Presenting a strong offer right out of the gate will give you the best chance to win.”

Second, show the seller you’re qualified to buy. You’ll want to have a pre-approval letter, but you can take it a step further by getting a full loan commitment letter, which verifies that your loan has already been underwritten and approved.

Third, give the seller time to move. Many sellers in our market are selling their property with the intention of moving into a new home, so they may be caught without a place to live once their property sells. If you wrote your offer and said that you would be willing to rent the property back for however long they need to find a new home, that will put you a step ahead of the other buyers.

Fourth, shorten or waive some of your contingency periods if you can. Having the least amount of contingency periods or shortening them will make you look stronger if you can pull that off.

Finally, write your best offer. A common strategy for sellers is to list the property lower than what they think it will sell for. That means the difference between the list price and the final sale price can be anywhere from 5% to 10%. When writing your offer, you don’t want to count on getting a counteroffer. Presenting a strong offer right out of the gate will give you a much better chance of getting your offer selected.

There are many other details that come into play during a home sale, so if you have any questions or are planning on buying or selling a home, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be glad to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+How+you+can+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+How+you+can+win+a+multiple+offer+situation.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re a buyer in a multiple offer situation, here are a few tips you can use to make your offer stronger than the ones you’re competing against.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re a buyer in a multiple offer situation, here are a few tips you can use to make your offer stronger than the ones you’re competing against.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Silicon Valley Market Is on Fire This 2nd Quarter</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/our-silicon-valley-market-is-on-fire-this-2nd-quarter.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-20 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+Your+Santa+Clara+2nd+quarter+market+update.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Our Silicon Valley market is on fire in the second quarter, especially if you’re a seller. 

Despite the fact that inventory has risen from 600 homes for sale back in December to roughly 1,200 at the current moment, it’s still near an all-time low. There’s a little bit more to choose from, but we have just one month of available inventory right now. 

Our average sale price is $1,000,050, and homes are sitting on the market an average of 20 days before they go under contract. In some areas, it’s a lot quicker than that. Interest rates are in the low 4% range, which is another all-time low. 

“Our market is on fire, especially if you’re a seller.”

What do these numbers mean?

If you’re a seller, it’s still a great time to enter the market. If you price your home correctly, present it correctly, and market it properly, you can expect multiple offers, which can drive up your final sale price. 

If you’re a buyer, you’re going to have your work cut out for you. I recently spoke to a fellow agent who received 19 offers on a listing of hers in San Jose, so it’s going to be tough to get your foot in the door against that level of competition. 

You should be ready to pay significantly more than the asking price for a home and come in strong with your terms. I also encourage you to explore other options than what’s listed on the MLS, Redfin, or Trulia. There are a lot of other sales happening off-market such as ‘For Sale By Owner’ properties and those that are sold between agents. 

If you have any other questions about our market or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, feel free to reach out to us. We’d love to help you. 
 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+Your+Santa+Clara+2nd+quarter+market+update.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate+Your+Santa+Clara+2nd+quarter+market+update.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Inventory is low, interest rates are low, and homes are selling fast in our market. Here’s what that means for buyers and sellers.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Inventory is low, interest rates are low, and homes are selling fast in our market. Here’s what that means for buyers and sellers.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Determine the Value of Your Silicon Valley Home</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/how-to-determine-the-value-of-your-silicon-valley-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-04-03 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+How+to+accurately+price+your+house+for+the+market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

What’s the best way to determine the value of your house when you’re getting ready to sell? I wanted to let you in on what we do on our team to determine a home’s value before it hits the market.

First, we’ll look at data from what has recently sold in the area. We’ll typically look back anywhere from three to six months to find sales to give us the most accurate price. We make sure we compare your home to other homes within 10% to 15% of your square footage.

“Comparing list prices to their actual sales price tells us how the market is moving in your neighborhood.”

Next, we want to make sure the homes we’re comparing to yours are in similar condition. For example, if your home is remodeled, we want to compare it to other homes that are remodeled or updated.

Finally, we’ll determine sales trends by comparing list prices and actual sales prices. Are homes selling well above asking price? Maybe they’re selling for less than the asking price. This will also tell us how fast homes are moving in the area. All these factors will help determine where we need to price your home.

I always recommend you have a professional real estate agent come out to your home for a thorough evaluation if you’re thinking about selling.

If you have any questions or you’d like one of our team members to evaluate your home, give us a call or send us an email. We’d love to help you out!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+How+to+accurately+price+your+house+for+the+market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+How+to+accurately+price+your+house+for+the+market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What's the best way to determine the value of your house when you're getting ready to sell? I wanted to let you in on what we do on our team to determine a home's value before it hits the market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What's the best way to determine the value of your house when you're getting ready to sell? I wanted to let you in on what we do on our team to determine a home's value before it hits the market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Estate Planning Isn't  Just for the Wealthy</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/estate-planning-isnt-just-for-the-wealthy.html</link>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-03-15 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Estate+Planning+Isnt+Just+for+the+Wealthy.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Estate planning is an important topic for everyone, so today I’m happy to be joined by David Park of estate planning firm Horner Park Law to help me discuss it.

Estate planning is a complete set of documents that typically includes a will or trust and other things that basically act as a set of instructions for what you want to happen to your property in the event you pass away or who you want to control it if you’re incapacitated.

The biggest misconception about estate planning is that it’s only for the wealthy.

“The biggest misconception about estate planning is that it’s only for the wealthy.”

While it’s true that the wealthy use estate planning to hold onto their wealth, the majority of people use estate planning to avoid probate, which is especially important to homeowners. If you have to go through probate, it takes a long time and costs a lot of money. The probate process usually takes a minimum of one year and can cost tens of thousands of dollars.

Probate can be tough because after a loved one passes away, it’s hard to move on when they’re tied up in the probate process in the court system.

We really feel strongly that setting up an estate plan is very important, and I’m actually setting up my estate plan with David. I want to share this with you, so we’ll have an estate planning seminar coming up with David and his firm where we’ll go over more details about the process and all the benefits. Stay tuned for more details.

If you have any questions for David in the meantime, you can reach him at 402-479-2312 or email him at dpark@hornerparklaw.com.

If you have any questions about buying or selling a home here in the Silicon Valley market, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to seeing you soon!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Estate+Planning+Isnt+Just+for+the+Wealthy.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Estate+Planning+Isnt+Just+for+the+Wealthy.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>What is estate planning and why is it so important? I'm joined today by estate attorney David Park to help me break it down for you.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>What is estate planning and why is it so important? I'm joined today by estate attorney David Park to help me break it down for you.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Avoid Damaging Your Credit Score With These Tips</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/avoid-damaging-your-credit-score-with-these-tips.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
          <category>Real Estate</category>
        
          <category>Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-30 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+We+don%E2%80%99t+want+your+score+to+be+ruined.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about buying a home or shopping for one right now, having the best credit score possible is in your best interest. To get you a lower score (which will get you a lower mortgage rate), here are the tips you should follow:

1. Check for any errors on your credit report. You can check it on annualcreditreport.com once a year for free. We see errors all the time on people’s reports. That can bring your credit score down.

2. Pay down your credit card bills as much as possible. If you can pay your debts off completely, that’s ideal. However, if you can pay it down by 30% or even 50%, you will be in much better shape

3. Never max out your credit cards. Doing so will always cause your score to drop

4. Wait 12 months to purchase after having credit issues. You want to have a clean, solid credit history for at least one year so that your score will start to go up again.

5. Shop for your mortgage interest rates at the same time. Ideally, you want to shop around to get the best rate. However, you need to do it in the same 30-day span. You will have to pull your credit for each lender, but if you’re shopping for the same type of mortgage in the same month, it will count as just one inquiry. This will bring your score down, but not by much.

“Never max out your credit card.”

I hope this information helps you if you have any questions about buying or selling a home. If you have any questions for me, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+We+don%E2%80%99t+want+your+score+to+be+ruined.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+We+don%E2%80%99t+want+your+score+to+be+ruined.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Having a good credit score is the key to getting a good mortgage. Here are five tips to help you keep your score high.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Having a good credit score is the key to getting a good mortgage. Here are five tips to help you keep your score high.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Ring in the New Year With These 2017 Market Predictions</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/ring-in-the-new-year-with-these-2017-market-predictions.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2017-01-18 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Real+estate+predictions+2017.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The new year is finally under way, so I wanted to give you my predictions for the 2017 Santa Clara real estate market. I’ll also give you a quick recap of what happened in 2016.

Additionally, I wanted to let you know how thankful we are for your support! We hope you had a fantastic New Year and we look forward to working with you this year.

So what did the market at the end of 2016 look like?

“Inventory is still incredibly low”

First, we saw a little under 15,000 home sales for the year. The average days on market was 37 days, and as of right now there are only about 580 listings, which is very low, and 900 homes pending. The big event was interest rates going up from mid 3% to between 4% and 4.5%, but those rates are still historically low.

What does this mean we can expect to see in 2017?

We can definitely expect to see home prices continue to increase, but we will see a decrease in sales. That’s because there is still a shortage of inventory. Right now we are still in a seller’s market, so buyers need to be strategic about finding a home.

If you have any questions about what’s going on in our market, please don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Real+estate+predictions+2017.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Real+estate+predictions+2017.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s a quick recap of our 2016 real estate market and my predictions for what to expect in 2017.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s a quick recap of our 2016 real estate market and my predictions for what to expect in 2017.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Why Are Seller Disclosures So Important?</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/why-are-seller-disclosures-so-important.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-12-13 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+An+essential+guide+to+disclosures.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I recently met with a seller who asked me what they should disclose about their home to their buyer. I wanted to answer that question for you today.

If you were to look up real estate lawsuits, you would see that a good portion of them have to do with seller disclosures, and sellers failing to disclose certain things they know about the property. Whether the roof is a tad leaky in one spot or there is a lot of traffic in the area, you need to disclose it all to the seller. Anything that you know about the property that will affect its marketability is required to be disclosed by law. Here are three tips to help you avoid situations of failing to disclose enough information to the seller.

“You are required by law to disclose anything you know.”

1. Keep up with the maintenance. We recommend keeping your systems up to date so that you are in-tune with the condition of your property.

2. Get a home inspection done. Having an inspection done before you list is a good idea. The inspector will come, tell you every little thing they find, and provide a nice report. This will also help minimize liability for you.

3. Offer a home warranty to the buyer. By doing this, you are saying that you’ll cover their main systems if they break down. The buyer will only have to pay a small deductible with a home warranty.

At the end of the day, disclose everything you can think of. You don’t want anything coming back to bite you. If you have any questions for me or you’re looking to buy or sell a home, give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+An+essential+guide+to+disclosures.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+An+essential+guide+to+disclosures.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Seller disclosures are not something to take lightly. You are required to disclose any defects or problems with your home before you sell.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Seller disclosures are not something to take lightly. You are required to disclose any defects or problems with your home before you sell.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Importance of Professional Photography</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/the-importance-of-professional-photography.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-11-16 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Using+photos+to+lure+online+home+buyers.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Professional photos of your home are extremely important when you list it for sale on the market.

In today’s world of real estate, 90% of buyers start their home search online. When they see your home on websites like Zillow and Redfin, the first thing they see is the photos. If your photos don’t make an amazing first impression, they will likely skip over it.

Sadly, there are a lot of agents out there who don’t hire professional photographers to shoot photos of their clients’ homes simply to save money. They don’t want to invest in the marketing, so they actually try to take the photos themselves.

Many of them are not good at taking photos, and many just use their smartphone to shoot pictures. I cannot tell you home many times I’ve seen photos of homes where you can see a Realtor in the mirror holding up their iPhone in the shot.

“You have to make an amazing first impression with online buyers.”

These photos come out horribly; they don’t pop and they don’t make the home stand out. The camera on an iPhone just won’t do your home justice, and the same goes for someone who doesn’t have experience shooting photos professionally.

You want to work with someone who knows how to work the lighting and the angles to show your home in its best light. The next time you work with a Realtor when selling a home, you need to ask whether they use professional photography. We invest thousands of dollars in professional photos for our clients.

I hope you found this tip helpful. If you have any more questions about marketing your home or about the Silicon Valley real estate market, give me a call anytime.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Using+photos+to+lure+online+home+buyers.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Enrique+Medellin/Silicon+Valley+Real+Estate-+Using+photos+to+lure+online+home+buyers.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>It may seem hard to believe, but 90% of buyers in today's world of real estate start their search online. Professionally shot photos of your home are the best way to make an impression on them.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>It may seem hard to believe, but 90% of buyers in today's world of real estate start their search online. Professionally shot photos of your home are the best way to make an impression on them.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's the Deal with Home Inspections?</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/whats-deal-with-home-inspections.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-22 11:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’m joined by Bruce Howe from House Master, who we’ve been working with for a number of years, to talk about inspections. Bruce has been in the business with House Master for 24 years, and they’ve done 79,000 inspections.

According to Bruce, the two most common inspections that homeowners should be aware of are termite inspections and home inspections, which have some similarities and differences. Both will point out things like earth-wood contact, wood damage, moisture content, and ventilation issues, but differ in that the home inspector can’t do any work on the home or solicit business on it. The termite inspector is supposed to create estimates in the report.
“The seller should expect that there will be issues from the inspection that will need to be worked out.”
As a seller, it’s important to make the inspection go smoothly by providing access to the crawl space (if the home has one), the attic, and the electrical panel. The seller should also expect that there will be issues from the inspection that will need to be worked out with the buyer. On the buyer side, they should make a point to read the inspection report from front to back - don’t rely solely on the verbal comments from the inspector. Buyers should also vet the inspector before choosing one. Home inspectors are only licensed in two-thirds of states so they may or may not be regulated. They should be trained and they should be insured.

What I like about House Master is that Bruce comes around the office twice a month, and they’re always up on the latest technology with a great website. They also provide reports that are really nice, easy to read and understand, and just makes it easier on the consumer. If you have questions or are looking for an inspection, feel free
to reach out to either one of us and we’ll be in touch!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I’m joined by Bruce Howe from House Master, who we’ve been working with for a number of years, to talk about inspections. Bruce has been in the business with House Master for 24 years, and they’ve done 79,000 inspections.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m joined by Bruce Howe from House Master, who we’ve been working with for a number of years, to talk about inspections. Bruce has been in the business with House Master for 24 years, and they’ve done 79,000 inspections.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Price to Sell this Summer in The Valley</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/price-to-sell-this-summer-in-valley.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-01 09:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about selling your home this summer in The Valley, you want to be sure you’re aware of how to price your home to sell. There needs to be a strategy, because there’s a difference between the price you’re trying to accomplish and the list price. Homes have a peak interest level in the first 30 days on the market, so it’s important to price correctly from the get-go to capture buzz in the first couple weeks.

There are three scenarios of pricing a home.

Group A: Priced too high because they think it’s worth more, and get less interest and fewer offers.

Group B: Priced right in the middle, and the home doesn’t necessarily stand out. Buyers compare your home to other similarly priced homes.

Group C: Homes priced a little less than what we expect to get. We feel this strategy works the best. If we price slightly less, it shows well, you have good marketing, and you have a great agent on your side, so you’re creating the perfect recipe for a bidding war.
“Homes have peak interest level in the first 30 days.”
You’ll get more people coming through, and more offers, which drives the price up. There are more details that come into play of course. If you have questions, please feel free to reach out to us.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you’re thinking about selling your home this summer in The Valley, you want to be sure you’re aware of how to price your home to sell. There needs to be a strategy, because there’s a difference between the price you’re trying to accomplish and the list price. Homes have a peak interest level in the first 30 days on the market, so it’s important to price correctly from the get-go to capture buzz in the first couple weeks.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re thinking about selling your home this summer in The Valley, you want to be sure you’re aware of how to price your home to sell. There needs to be a strategy, because there’s a difference between the price you’re trying to accomplish and the list price. Homes have a peak interest level in the first 30 days on the market, so it’s important to price correctly from the get-go to capture buzz in the first couple weeks.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2nd Quarter Silicon Valley Market Update</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/2nd-quarter-silicon-valley-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-15 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’re onto the second quarter in the Santa Clara County real estate market, so I wanted to give you a quick update.

When we last checked on the market, inventory was just over 1,000 homes, average price was around $860,000, average days on market sat about 69, and the interest rates were sitting around 3.75%. So what’s happened since then? Well, we’re entering a presidential election, and the Federal Reserve increased interest rates. People thought this would increase mortgage interest rates, but they actually came down a little bit.
“Don’t give up hope!”
Starting in the second quarter, homes on the market have gone up by 700, price is up to $931,000, and the average days on market has fallen to 41, and of course, interest rates are down around the 3.625% range for 30-year fixed mortgages. This means we’re still in a seller’s market, but there is some more inventory. In some areas, we’re starting to see homes get fewer offers, but it’s still very competitive and sellers are still getting top dollar quickly.

If you’re looking to sell, it’s still a good time, and if you’re looking to buy, there’s more inventory for you. Don’t give up hope! You just need to partner with the right agent.

Thanks again for your support. If you have any questions, please feel free to get in touch and we’ll talk soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We’re onto the second quarter in the Santa Clara County real estate market, so I wanted to give you a quick update.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’re onto the second quarter in the Santa Clara County real estate market, so I wanted to give you a quick update.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can Zillow Give You an Accurate Home Value?</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/silicon-valley-real-estate-zestimates.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-27 16:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’ve been getting the question “Is Zillow an accurate place to find my home’s value?” a lot, and today we are going to explain how it works and what it is useful for.

Here’s what Zillow is good for. Number one, it’s probably the most widely-used commercially marketed real estate search engine. Studies have shown that 70-75% of buyers visit the site. Zillow also offers an automated home value feature that they call a Zestimate. Zestimates are good jumping off points, but they’re just estimates.

Zestimates do not take into account your property’s condition, or all the recent sales in your area. The algorithm can’t determine any updates or renovations you have done, and oftentimes it uses sold data that’s over a year old.

When a professional agent like one of us comes to your home, we are going to take notice of every detail, and assess your home on the current market using the latest sold data and up-to-date information. This will give us the best indication of where to price your home to sell for top dollar.
“Only a professional can give you an accurate valuation.”
These are all things that should be taken into account when trying to pinpoint your value. Zillow is a great starting point, but if you’re looking to make a certain amount of money on your sale, you definitely want to contact a professional. If you have any questions at all, feel free to reach out to us via phone or email. We are always here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

We’ve been getting the question “Is Zillow an accurate place to find my home’s value?” a lot, and today we are going to explain how it works and what it is useful for.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’ve been getting the question “Is Zillow an accurate place to find my home’s value?” a lot, and today we are going to explain how it works and what it is useful for.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can Security Systems Help Sell Your Silicon Valley Home?</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/silicon-valley-real-estate-home-security.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-19 11:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I have Angel Orozco from Skyline Security and he’s going to be talking about home security systems and how they can actually help your home sell in Silicon Valley.

Skyline Security has been around for fifteen years and they specialize in all of the newer and more advanced security systems. Many of these are controlled via smartphones and they can be used commercially or residentially.

Technology is huge in security and Skyline offers fully automated technology. Using your phone to set your alarm is extremely convenient, and you can even lock doors with their app. You can secure your entire home from your phone. Motion sensors can detect movement and they also have sensors to detect glass breaking.
“Buyers like to see security systems installed.”
We have just formed a partnership with Skyline Security and anyone who buys a home from us will get a free installation from Skyline Security. If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to Angel.

We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today I have Angel Orozco from Skyline Security and he’s going to be talking about home security systems and how they can actually help your home sell in Silicon Valley.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I have Angel Orozco from Skyline Security and he’s going to be talking about home security systems and how they can actually help your home sell in Silicon Valley.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Four Tips for First-Time Silicon Valley Home Buyers</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/silicon-valley-real-estate-first-time.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-24 11:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today, we’ll be discussing four valuable tips for first-time home buyers in the surrounding Silicon Valley area. Blanca Medellin, a real estate buying agent on our team, joins us to discuss important advice for first-time home buyers. If you’re looking to purchase a home this spring, this is especially relevant to you!

1. Save up for your down payment. In today’s conditions, most lenders require anywhere from 3% to 30% in a down payment. Be prepared to pay more than you initially anticipate.

2. Consider any home improvement or other expenses. The total cost is not only your mortgage payment, but utility, landscaping, maintenance, and other monthly bills.

3. Shop around for a mortgage. Find someone you’re comfortable with. Review your finances and share your goals to obtain a prequalification letter.

4. Get educated on the home buying process. Sit down with us for a one-on-one consultation, free of charge and obligation. We’ll walk you through every step and what you should expect.
“Get Educated on the home buying process.”
If you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in the area, give me a call or send me an email today. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Today, we’ll be discussing four valuable tips for first-time home buyers in the surrounding Silicon Valley area. Blanca Medellin, a real estate buying agent on our team, joins us to discuss important advice for first-time home buyers. If you’re looking to purchase a home this spring, this is especially relevant to you!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, we’ll be discussing four valuable tips for first-time home buyers in the surrounding Silicon Valley area. Blanca Medellin, a real estate buying agent on our team, joins us to discuss important advice for first-time home buyers. If you’re looking to purchase a home this spring, this is especially relevant to you!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Sell Your Home Before Buying a New One?</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/silicon-valley-buy-sell-same-time.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-16 11:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you plan on selling your current house and buying a new one, there are a few things you need to take into consideration.

The first question to ask is whether you need the equity from your current property in order to purchase a new property. If the answer is yes, we suggest you list the property you’re living in first, in order to have the purchasing power necessary to buy your next home.

If you have the cash in the bank to buy your next home without having to sell, it’s a great position to be in. In that case, you can go ahead and start looking at properties before you even list. However, you should be aware of the possibility that you might have two mortgages at the same time.

Regardless of what you end up doing, it’s crucial to be aware of market conditions. **Here in Silicon Valley, it’s a very competitive market there is a lot of inventory and there are a lot of buyers. In this situation, putting an offer on a home that is contingent on you selling your current home is not going to make you look as powerful as someone else who has already sold their home and has some money in the bank.
“Regardless of what you end up doing, it’s crucial to be aware of market conditions.”
In this market, sellers need to be aware of something called rent-backs. Basically, a rent-back is a situation in which the seller asks the buyer to rent back the property from the new buyers. This agreement extends the closing so that sellers can remain in their house, while paying rent to the buyer, as they finalize their new living situation. Many sellers have found this to be a great way to purchase a new home without having to move more than once.

If you have questions about how you can make your move as smooth as possible, or if you have any questions about our local market, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would love to give you a hand!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

If you plan on selling your current house and buying a new one, there are a few things you need to take into consideration.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you plan on selling your current house and buying a new one, there are a few things you need to take into consideration.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Silicon Valley Home Ready to Sell This Spring?</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/silicon-valley-real-estate-spring-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-02-25 15:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
The busiest selling season is approaching quickly. Today, we’ll go over five ways to prepare your home to sell this spring. These tips will help your property make the best first impression on potential buyers.

1. Paint the walls a neutral color and replace the carpet. Stick to beige and grays to appeal to the masses. Stay away from loud and bright colors.

2. Remove clutter. Depersonalize the property. Take down family photos and get rid of personal belongings. You’re going to have to pack them anyway, and with them put away, buyers can envision themselves living in the home.

3. Stage your home. If you’re still living in the property, we can do partial staging. If the home is vacant, we can fully stage the property. Staging will give the property a clean, cohesive design and create a nice flow for people walking through the property.

4. Add exterior curb appeal. The grass should be trimmed and shrubs should be pruned. Add fresh flowers and plants. Repaint the front facade, trim, and front door. This will do wonders for how your property shows online and what buyers see when they pull up to your home.

5. Get a home inspection. A home inspection will tell you if anything is wrong with the property. Then you can decide if you want to address those issues up front or make adjustments in the price before listing your home. It’s better to know what’s wrong with the home rather than finding out during negotiations with the buyer, which can save you thousands of dollars.

“Stage your home to appeal to more buyers.”

If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>
The busiest selling season is approaching quickly. Today, we’ll go over five ways to prepare your home to sell this spring. These tips will help your property make the best first impression on potential buyers.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
The busiest selling season is approaching quickly. Today, we’ll go over five ways to prepare your home to sell this spring. These tips will help your property make the best first impression on potential buyers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Questions to Ask an Agent Before Hiring Them</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/santa-clara-real-estate-agent-questions.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Questions</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-01-13 13:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

When it comes time for you to hire a real estate agent, you have almost too many options. Today we are going to discuss the top 5 questions you should be asking any real estate agent before you hire them, so you can filter through the plethora of agents out there in order to find the right one for you.

1. Are you a full-time agent? There are a lot of part-time agents out there; unfortunately, they don’t have the necessary time or experience to provide good service.** Here at PRG Real Estate, we are all full-time agents, **and we are always working our hardest to give you the best service possible.

2. What kind of operation do you run? A lot of agents attempt to do everything themselves. This is not an efficient process, which is why many solo agents aren’t able to give their clients the service they deserve. We have a team of specialized individuals that is designed to make your transaction one smooth process. Our support staff is in place to free up time for our agents so they can spend that time helping you buy or sell a home.
3. Do you have client testimonials? We survey all of our clients each year and ask their honest opinions about working with us. We appreciate all the feedback that we get, positive or negative, and use it to improve our business. Any agent you hire should be doing the same.

4. Do you have a marketing plan? Marketing listings is crucial in our market, and we know that. **That’s why we have our own personalized marketing plan **which details our proven strategies and cutting edge marketing techniques that will net top dollar for your home.

5. What percentage of your business comes from referrals? A good agent should have happy customers that want to come back and do business again, or refer their friends and family members. About 30-40% of our business comes from referrals and previous clients, and we take great pride in that.
“Here at PRG Real Estate, we are all full-time agents.”
Thanks for joining me today. If you have any questions about this topic, or are looking to buy or sell in Silicon Valley, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

When it comes time for you to hire a real estate agent, you have almost too many options. Today we are going to discuss the top 5 questions you should be asking any real estate agent before you hire them, so you can filter through the plethora of agents out there in order to find the right one for you.

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When it comes time for you to hire a real estate agent, you have almost too many options. Today we are going to discuss the top 5 questions you should be asking any real estate agent before you hire them, so you can filter through the plethora of agents out there in order to find the right one for you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's Happening with Santa Clara County Real Estate?</title>
        <link>http://prg-re.blog/santa-clara-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-01-11 10:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Currently, there are just over 1,000 active homes on the market. The average sales price is $860,000, and homes spend an average of 69 days on the market. In more desirable areas, homes are on the market for one or two weeks!

Inventory is extremely low right now, with about one month of inventory on the market. Since there is a shortage of inventory, home values are going up. Many sellers are receiving multiple offers, especially in desirable areas with
good schools and great amenities nearby.

Interest rates remain at all-time lows, hovering in the high threes and low fours for a 30-year fixed mortgage. Buyers have a lot more purchasing power right now, so take advantage of these low rates.
“Low inventory means you can sell for top dollar!”
What does this mean for you? If you’re looking to sell, you can get top dollar for your home so long as you are priced correctly and have an aggressive marketing plan.

For buyers, the market is quite competitive. It might take a little while to get you into a home, but we can come up with a plan to get you to the closing table. Plus, those interest rates are fantastic!

If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://prg-re.blog" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>

Currently, there are just over 1,000 active homes on the market. The average sales price is $860,000, and homes spend an average of 69 days on the market. In more desirable areas, homes are on the market for one or two weeks!

</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Currently, there are just over 1,000 active homes on the market. The average sales price is $860,000, and homes spend an average of 69 days on the market. In more desirable areas, homes are on the market for one or two weeks!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Enrique Medellin</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Enrique Medellin</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from PRG Real Estate.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
