<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>PRG Real Estate Podcast</title>
    <link>http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Durwin Homes Group - your professional San Jose Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Enrique Medellin</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2016-11-10 11:15:55 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Enrique Medellin</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.comhttp://i.imgur.com/DUtCRwl.png"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">News &amp; Politics</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>info@realestatePRG.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Enrique Medellin</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.comhttp://i.imgur.com/DUtCRwl.png"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Jose Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Durwin Homes Group - your professional San Jose Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="News &amp; Politics"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>What's the Deal with Home Inspections?</title>
        <link>http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com/whats-deal-with-home-inspections.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-22 11:23:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I’m joined by Bruce Howe from House Master, who we’ve been working with for a number of years, to talk about inspections. Bruce has been in the business with House Master for 24 years, and they’ve done 79,000 inspections.

According to Bruce, the two most common inspections that homeowners should be aware of are termite inspections and home inspections, which have some similarities and differences. Both will point out things like earth-wood contact, wood damage, moisture content, and ventilation issues, but differ in that the home inspector can’t do any work on the home or solicit business on it. The termite inspector is supposed to create estimates in the report.
“The seller should expect that there will be issues from the inspection that will need to be worked out.”
As a seller, it’s important to make the inspection go smoothly by providing access to the crawl space (if the home has one), the attic, and the electrical panel. The seller should also expect that there will be issues from the inspection that will need to be worked out with the buyer. On the buyer side, they should make a point to read the inspection report from front to back - don’t rely solely on the verbal comments from the inspector. Buyers should also vet the inspector before choosing one. Home inspectors are only licensed in two-thirds of states so they may or may not be regulated. They should be trained and they should be insured.

What I like about House Master is that Bruce comes around the office twice a month, and they’re always up on the latest technology with a great website. They also provide reports that are really nice, easy to read and understand, and just makes it easier on the consumer. If you have questions or are looking for an inspection, feel free
to reach out to either one of us and we’ll be in touch!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Jose Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I’m joined by Bruce Howe from House Master, who we’ve been working with for a number of years, to talk about inspections. Bruce has been in the business with House Master for 24 years, and they’ve done 79,000 inspections.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Price to Sell this Summer in The Valley</title>
        <link>http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com/price-to-sell-this-summer-in-valley.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-07-01 09:57:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you’re thinking about selling your home this summer in The Valley, you want to be sure you’re aware of how to price your home to sell. There needs to be a strategy, because there’s a difference between the price you’re trying to accomplish and the list price. Homes have a peak interest level in the first 30 days on the market, so it’s important to price correctly from the get-go to capture buzz in the first couple weeks.

There are three scenarios of pricing a home.

Group A: Priced too high because they think it’s worth more, and get less interest and fewer offers.

Group B: Priced right in the middle, and the home doesn’t necessarily stand out. Buyers compare your home to other similarly priced homes.

Group C: Homes priced a little less than what we expect to get. We feel this strategy works the best. If we price slightly less, it shows well, you have good marketing, and you have a great agent on your side, so you’re creating the perfect recipe for a bidding war.
“Homes have peak interest level in the first 30 days.”
You’ll get more people coming through, and more offers, which drives the price up. There are more details that come into play of course. If you have questions, please feel free to reach out to us.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Jose Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you’re thinking about selling your home this summer in The Valley, you want to be sure you’re aware of how to price your home to sell. There needs to be a strategy, because there’s a difference between the price you’re trying to accomplish and the list price. Homes have a peak interest level in the first 30 days on the market, so it’s important to price correctly from the get-go to capture buzz in the first couple weeks.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2nd Quarter Silicon Valley Market Update</title>
        <link>http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com/2nd-quarter-silicon-valley-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Updates</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-06-15 14:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’re onto the second quarter in the Santa Clara County real estate market, so I wanted to give you a quick update.

When we last checked on the market, inventory was just over 1,000 homes, average price was around $860,000, average days on market sat about 69, and the interest rates were sitting around 3.75%. So what’s happened since then? Well, we’re entering a presidential election, and the Federal Reserve increased interest rates. People thought this would increase mortgage interest rates, but they actually came down a little bit.
“Don’t give up hope!”
Starting in the second quarter, homes on the market have gone up by 700, price is up to $931,000, and the average days on market has fallen to 41, and of course, interest rates are down around the 3.625% range for 30-year fixed mortgages. This means we’re still in a seller’s market, but there is some more inventory. In some areas, we’re starting to see homes get fewer offers, but it’s still very competitive and sellers are still getting top dollar quickly.

If you’re looking to sell, it’s still a good time, and if you’re looking to buy, there’s more inventory for you. Don’t give up hope! You just need to partner with the right agent.

Thanks again for your support. If you have any questions, please feel free to get in touch and we’ll talk soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Jose Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’re onto the second quarter in the Santa Clara County real estate market, so I wanted to give you a quick update.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Can Zillow Give You an Accurate Home Value?</title>
        <link>http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com/silicon-valley-real-estate-zestimates.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-27 16:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

We’ve been getting the question “Is Zillow an accurate place to find my home’s value?” a lot, and today we are going to explain how it works and what it is useful for.

Here’s what Zillow is good for. Number one, it’s probably the most widely-used commercially marketed real estate search engine. Studies have shown that 70-75% of buyers visit the site. Zillow also offers an automated home value feature that they call a Zestimate. Zestimates are good jumping off points, but they’re just estimates.

Zestimates do not take into account your property’s condition, or all the recent sales in your area. The algorithm can’t determine any updates or renovations you have done, and oftentimes it uses sold data that’s over a year old.

When a professional agent like one of us comes to your home, we are going to take notice of every detail, and assess your home on the current market using the latest sold data and up-to-date information. This will give us the best indication of where to price your home to sell for top dollar.
“Only a professional can give you an accurate valuation.”
These are all things that should be taken into account when trying to pinpoint your value. Zillow is a great starting point, but if you’re looking to make a certain amount of money on your sale, you definitely want to contact a professional. If you have any questions at all, feel free to reach out to us via phone or email. We are always here to help.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Jose Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

We’ve been getting the question “Is Zillow an accurate place to find my home’s value?” a lot, and today we are going to explain how it works and what it is useful for.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can Security Systems Help Sell Your Silicon Valley Home?</title>
        <link>http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com/silicon-valley-real-estate-home-security.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-04-19 11:22:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today I have Angel Orozco from Skyline Security and he’s going to be talking about home security systems and how they can actually help your home sell in Silicon Valley.

Skyline Security has been around for fifteen years and they specialize in all of the newer and more advanced security systems. Many of these are controlled via smartphones and they can be used commercially or residentially.

Technology is huge in security and Skyline offers fully automated technology. Using your phone to set your alarm is extremely convenient, and you can even lock doors with their app. You can secure your entire home from your phone. Motion sensors can detect movement and they also have sensors to detect glass breaking.
“Buyers like to see security systems installed.”
We have just formed a partnership with Skyline Security and anyone who buys a home from us will get a free installation from Skyline Security. If you have any questions, please don’t hesitate to reach out to Angel.

We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Jose Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today I have Angel Orozco from Skyline Security and he’s going to be talking about home security systems and how they can actually help your home sell in Silicon Valley.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Four Tips for First-Time Silicon Valley Home Buyers</title>
        <link>http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com/silicon-valley-real-estate-first-time.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-24 11:46:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Today, we’ll be discussing four valuable tips for first-time home buyers in the surrounding Silicon Valley area. Blanca Medellin, a real estate buying agent on our team, joins us to discuss important advice for first-time home buyers. If you’re looking to purchase a home this spring, this is especially relevant to you!

1. Save up for your down payment. In today’s conditions, most lenders require anywhere from 3% to 30% in a down payment. Be prepared to pay more than you initially anticipate.

2. Consider any home improvement or other expenses. The total cost is not only your mortgage payment, but utility, landscaping, maintenance, and other monthly bills.

3. Shop around for a mortgage. Find someone you’re comfortable with. Review your finances and share your goals to obtain a prequalification letter.

4. Get educated on the home buying process. Sit down with us for a one-on-one consultation, free of charge and obligation. We’ll walk you through every step and what you should expect.
“Get Educated on the home buying process.”
If you’re thinking about buying or selling a home in the area, give me a call or send me an email today. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Jose Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Today, we’ll be discussing four valuable tips for first-time home buyers in the surrounding Silicon Valley area. Blanca Medellin, a real estate buying agent on our team, joins us to discuss important advice for first-time home buyers. If you’re looking to purchase a home this spring, this is especially relevant to you!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Should You Sell Your Home Before Buying a New One?</title>
        <link>http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com/silicon-valley-buy-sell-same-time.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-03-16 11:50:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

If you plan on selling your current house and buying a new one, there are a few things you need to take into consideration.

The first question to ask is whether you need the equity from your current property in order to purchase a new property. If the answer is yes, we suggest you list the property you’re living in first, in order to have the purchasing power necessary to buy your next home.

If you have the cash in the bank to buy your next home without having to sell, it’s a great position to be in. In that case, you can go ahead and start looking at properties before you even list. However, you should be aware of the possibility that you might have two mortgages at the same time.

Regardless of what you end up doing, it’s crucial to be aware of market conditions. **Here in Silicon Valley, it’s a very competitive market there is a lot of inventory and there are a lot of buyers. In this situation, putting an offer on a home that is contingent on you selling your current home is not going to make you look as powerful as someone else who has already sold their home and has some money in the bank.
“Regardless of what you end up doing, it’s crucial to be aware of market conditions.”
In this market, sellers need to be aware of something called rent-backs. Basically, a rent-back is a situation in which the seller asks the buyer to rent back the property from the new buyers. This agreement extends the closing so that sellers can remain in their house, while paying rent to the buyer, as they finalize their new living situation. Many sellers have found this to be a great way to purchase a new home without having to move more than once.

If you have questions about how you can make your move as smooth as possible, or if you have any questions about our local market, please don’t hesitate to reach out to us. We would love to give you a hand!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Jose Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

If you plan on selling your current house and buying a new one, there are a few things you need to take into consideration.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Is Your Silicon Valley Home Ready to Sell This Spring?</title>
        <link>http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com/silicon-valley-real-estate-spring-sell.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Seller Tips</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-02-25 15:20:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>
The busiest selling season is approaching quickly. Today, we’ll go over five ways to prepare your home to sell this spring. These tips will help your property make the best first impression on potential buyers.

1. Paint the walls a neutral color and replace the carpet. Stick to beige and grays to appeal to the masses. Stay away from loud and bright colors.

2. Remove clutter. Depersonalize the property. Take down family photos and get rid of personal belongings. You’re going to have to pack them anyway, and with them put away, buyers can envision themselves living in the home.

3. Stage your home. If you’re still living in the property, we can do partial staging. If the home is vacant, we can fully stage the property. Staging will give the property a clean, cohesive design and create a nice flow for people walking through the property.

4. Add exterior curb appeal. The grass should be trimmed and shrubs should be pruned. Add fresh flowers and plants. Repaint the front facade, trim, and front door. This will do wonders for how your property shows online and what buyers see when they pull up to your home.

5. Get a home inspection. A home inspection will tell you if anything is wrong with the property. Then you can decide if you want to address those issues up front or make adjustments in the price before listing your home. It’s better to know what’s wrong with the home rather than finding out during negotiations with the buyer, which can save you thousands of dollars.

“Stage your home to appeal to more buyers.”

If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email. We would be happy to help you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Jose Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>
The busiest selling season is approaching quickly. Today, we’ll go over five ways to prepare your home to sell this spring. These tips will help your property make the best first impression on potential buyers.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>5 Questions to Ask an Agent Before Hiring Them</title>
        <link>http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com/santa-clara-real-estate-agent-questions.html</link>
        
          <category>Agent Questions</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-01-13 13:09:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

When it comes time for you to hire a real estate agent, you have almost too many options. Today we are going to discuss the top 5 questions you should be asking any real estate agent before you hire them, so you can filter through the plethora of agents out there in order to find the right one for you.

1. Are you a full-time agent? There are a lot of part-time agents out there; unfortunately, they don’t have the necessary time or experience to provide good service.** Here at PRG Real Estate, we are all full-time agents, **and we are always working our hardest to give you the best service possible.

2. What kind of operation do you run? A lot of agents attempt to do everything themselves. This is not an efficient process, which is why many solo agents aren’t able to give their clients the service they deserve. We have a team of specialized individuals that is designed to make your transaction one smooth process. Our support staff is in place to free up time for our agents so they can spend that time helping you buy or sell a home.
3. Do you have client testimonials? We survey all of our clients each year and ask their honest opinions about working with us. We appreciate all the feedback that we get, positive or negative, and use it to improve our business. Any agent you hire should be doing the same.

4. Do you have a marketing plan? Marketing listings is crucial in our market, and we know that. **That’s why we have our own personalized marketing plan **which details our proven strategies and cutting edge marketing techniques that will net top dollar for your home.

5. What percentage of your business comes from referrals? A good agent should have happy customers that want to come back and do business again, or refer their friends and family members. About 30-40% of our business comes from referrals and previous clients, and we take great pride in that.
“Here at PRG Real Estate, we are all full-time agents.”
Thanks for joining me today. If you have any questions about this topic, or are looking to buy or sell in Silicon Valley, give us a call or send us an email. We would love to hear from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Jose Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

When it comes time for you to hire a real estate agent, you have almost too many options. Today we are going to discuss the top 5 questions you should be asking any real estate agent before you hire them, so you can filter through the plethora of agents out there in order to find the right one for you.

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What's Happening with Santa Clara County Real Estate?</title>
        <link>http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com/santa-clara-real-estate-market-update.html</link>
        
          <category>Market Update</category>
        
        <author>Enrique Medellin</author>
        <pubDate>2016-01-11 10:52:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Currently, there are just over 1,000 active homes on the market. The average sales price is $860,000, and homes spend an average of 69 days on the market. In more desirable areas, homes are on the market for one or two weeks!

Inventory is extremely low right now, with about one month of inventory on the market. Since there is a shortage of inventory, home values are going up. Many sellers are receiving multiple offers, especially in desirable areas with
good schools and great amenities nearby.

Interest rates remain at all-time lows, hovering in the high threes and low fours for a 30-year fixed mortgage. Buyers have a lot more purchasing power right now, so take advantage of these low rates.
“Low inventory means you can sell for top dollar!”
What does this mean for you? If you’re looking to sell, you can get top dollar for your home so long as you are priced correctly and have an aggressive marketing plan.

For buyers, the market is quite competitive. It might take a little while to get you into a home, but we can come up with a plan to get you to the closing table. Plus, those interest rates are fantastic!

If you have any questions, give us a call or send us an email. We look forward to hearing from you!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://treasuredavisrealestateadvisors.com" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the San Jose Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Enrique Medellin</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>

Currently, there are just over 1,000 active homes on the market. The average sales price is $860,000, and homes spend an average of 69 days on the market. In more desirable areas, homes are on the market for one or two weeks!

</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in San Jose, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Enrique Medellin</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Enrique Medellin</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Durwin Homes Group - your professional San Jose Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>